Guide to the Marine Workers Historical Collection TAM 125
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Marine Workers Historical Collection
1930-1996
TAM 125
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
5.0 linear feet (5 boxes)
The Marine Workers Historical Collection was the result of a community history project on the Chelsea area of New York City conducted by Joe Doyle, then a New York University Department of Public History graduate student, beginning in 1981. Doyle set out to reconstruct and document the working-class population and institutions of the Chelsea waterfront of New York City in the first half of the twentieth century. The project was continued and expanded in partnership with the Marine Workers Historical Association. The collection includes rank-and-file newsletters, flyers, union correspondence, grievance reports, pamphlets, memoirs, memorabilia and printed ephemera of many kinds documenting the working and living conditions of American merchant seamen/women since 1900 and the struggle of maritime workers, particularly sympathizers of the Left, to organize and maintain leadership in the National Maritime Union (NMU) and other unions.
Marine Workers Historical Association (U.S.).
Provenance
The material in this collection was donated to the Tamiment Library, NYU as a result of collecting efforts by Joe Doyle, working with the Marine Workers Historical Association, in a series of donations beginning in 1982. The provenance of a number of individual items is recorded in the Library’s accession file for the collection.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Marine Workers Historical Collection was the result of a community history project on the Chelsea area of New York City conducted by Joe Doyle, then a New York University Department of Public History graduate student, beginning in 1981. Doyle set out to reconstruct and document the working-class population and institutions of the Chelsea waterfront of New York City in the first half of the twentieth century. Chelsea was a center of shipping and there was a sizable Irish presence in the area. Through walking tours, lectures, plays and locally published articles, Doyle examined the role of Irish politicians and maritime workers in the fabric of a neighborhood. Through oral history interviews, he learned that many founders of the National Maritime Union shipped out from the hiring halls of Chelsea. Doyle’s grant application, project reports and an article in Public History(Vol. I, l984) explain the difficulties of trying to research the maritime history of a community that in some instances did not want that history written. During his second year of work on the project Doyle joined forces with the Marine Workers Historical Association, which was actively collecting documentary material.
In 1979, some sixty former seamen and longshoremen had formed the Marine Workers Historical Association to bring together those who had been engaged in the organizing efforts on waterfront and on shipboard in the 1930s, to preserve their history through documents and written and oral accounts by participants, and to make that history more widely known. The first issue of their newsletter, The Hawsepipe(Nov Dec, 1981), included a reference to the Tamiment Library's interest in adding documents, personal histories, photographs, etc. to its archives. Because many American seamen had shipped out of the Chelsea area, Joe Doyle had included MWHA seamen in his Chelsea research activities and he became a central contact person and chief solicitor of much of the current collection. The collection continues to seek out and accept donations of material.
Scope and Content Note
The Marine Workers Historical Collection includes rank-and-file newsletters, flyers, union correspondence, grievance reports, pamphlets, memoirs, memorabilia and printed ephemera of many kinds documenting the working and living conditions of American merchant seamen/women since 1900 and the struggle of maritime workers, particularly sympathizers of the Left, to organize and maintain leadership in the National Maritime Union (NMU) and other unions.
Of particular note are files of clippings relating to NMU president Joseph Curran and critiques of the Curran administration produced by rank-and-file opposition groups and individuals. Outstanding among these is a 350-page typescript memoir by Edward Gordon entitled "Where Away." Gordon describes in detail his upbringing in a Russian immigrant family and his twenty-four years at sea. He discusses early organizing efforts, the hardships of life at sea and power struggles within the union.
A series of files documents the International Seaman’s Union strike of 1936, and a small amount of material on Harry Bridges, president of the International Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen’s Union and Paul Hall, president of the Seamen’s International Union, are also included. Notable among the rank-and-file activists whose experience is documented are Bill Bailey, Barney Lynch, Frederick N. (Blackie) Myers, Stanley Postek, and Morris Weiner. The structure and development of Joe Doyle’s Chelsea Waterfront History Project and the administrative history of the Marine Workers Historical Association are also well represented in the collection.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Files are grouped into one series:
I, General Files, 1930-1996
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John Gladstone Papers (Wagner #146)
Jake Green Photograph Collection. (Photo #47).
International Longshoremen’s Association: Reference Files of the International Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen’s Union. (Wagner #55).
Marine Workers Historical Photograph Collection (Photo #200).
Marine Workers Oral History Collection. (OH #30).
National Maritime Union Photograph Collection (Photo #44).
National Maritime Union and Seafarers International Union: Reference Files of the International Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen’s Union. (Wagner #267).
New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection (OH #1)
Clarence Reed Papers (Wagner #15)
Randall B. (Pete) Smith: Maritime Radicalism Collection (Tamiment# 203).
Henry Spira Papers. (Tamiment #418).
Bailey, Bill; Bridges, Harry, 1901-; Curran, Joseph Edwin, 1906-1981; Doyle, Joe.; Hall, Paul.; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.; International Seamen's Union of America.; Marine Cooks and Stewards Association of the Pacific Coast.; Marine Workers Historical Association (U.S.).; National Maritime Union of America.; Postek, Stanley, 1912-1991; Seafarers International Union of North America.; Wirtz, Willard, 1912-; Biographical sketches.; Clippings (information artifacts); Contracts.; Correspondence.; Fliers (printed matter); Merchant mariners |x Labor unions |z United States; Minutes.; New York (N.Y.); Reports.
- Series I: General Files, 1930-1996
  - Alexander, Gus: Society’s Stepchildren Fight Back!: The Story of the Scandinavian Seamen in America(pamphlet), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Merchant Fleet Informational Pamphlet for Sailors (untitled), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bailey, Bill: Articles by and about, 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bailey, Bill: “Marine Workers Historical Association Honors the Life of its President” (spiral bound book, photocopy), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bailey, Bill: "Odyssey (Voyage) of the Morning Star," Unpublished Novel (typescript), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bailey, Bill: Promotion for Autobiography, Kid from Hoboken, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baker, M. D.: "Tanker Strike" Card, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Boano, Danny: Drafts of Unpublished Memoirs, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Inquiry on Long-shore Industry Work Stoppage, October-November 1951, Port of New York(photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bolmarcich, John P.: Letter to Pilot Editor, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bolmarcich, John P.: "Tuberculosis and Seamen" (marked up for publication in The Hawsepipe), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bridges, Harry: Correspondence with Gil Mers, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bridges, Harry: Correspondence with Julius Margolin, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bridges, Harry: Clippings, 1936-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bridges, Harry: Open Letter to Joseph Curran and NMU Officers about West Coast Maritime Strike, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Longshoremen "Outlaw" Strike: Clippings, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: "A Political History of a Modern Agent-Provocateur," Book Proposal, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Administrative, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Report of Commission on Industrial Relations(pp. 2053-2199), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Hobo News(photocopies), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Joe Doyle Publications, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Research Materials, undated, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Copeland, Bill: "Protest the Copeland Bill" Cards, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Curran, Joseph: Clippings, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Curran, Joseph: Clippings (I), 1960s (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Curran, Joseph: Clippings (II), 1960s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Curran, Joseph: Clippings (III), 1960s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Curran, Joseph: ILA Longshore Election Press Release, Oct 16, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Curran, Joseph: The Membership Wins Again, NMU Pamphlet, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Curran, Joseph: "NMU President Discusses Problems of U. S. Merchant Marine," NYS Industrial Bulletin(photocopy), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Curran, Joseph: Signed letter to Daily Worker about Roy Hudson, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Curran, Joseph: "What is the Rank and File Caucus? ," Flyer (photocopy), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Curran, Joseph et al v. Morrissey and Ibrahim: Briefs, Clippings, Pamphlet, Notes, and U. S. District Court Decision, 1969-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Daily Worker Clipping: Chalk Drawings of Noted Marine Workers (Stanley Postek, Tex Drake, Benny Foster, Ann Russell, Captain Hugh Mulzac, and Alfonse G. Wolfe), Jul 18, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dockers News: ILA Dissidents (photocopies), Mar 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Forrey, Eddie: "Peace of Mind," Poetry, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gavin, James (Jimmy): Memoirs and Poetry (unpublished), 1939-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gordon, Edward: Monograph on Maritime History in Latin America (typescript) (I), undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gordon, Edward: Monograph (II), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gordon, Edward: NMU Special Representative Confirmation Letter, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Gordon, Edward: "Where Away: A Narrative by Edward Gordon," Unpublished Memoir (pp. 1-122), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gordon, Edward: "Where Away" (pp. 123-224), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Gordon, Edward: "Where Away" (pp. 225-336), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gordon, Edward: "Where Away" Research and Appendices, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Grant, George and Al Smith: Brief Biographical Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Green, Thomas (Tommy): Memoir (typescript), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Grey, Barry: Correspondence with Morris Weiner, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hall, Paul: Clippings, 1962, 1971, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hall, Paul: Murray Kempton Tribute, Clipping, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hall, Paul: Telegram re: U. S. Department of Labor Anniversary Dinner (photocopy), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hawsepipe, Newsletter of the Marine Workers Historical Association: Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Hawsepipe: Indexes and Table of Contents, 1981-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hawsepipe(Vol. I, No. 1), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hawsepipe(Vol. III, No. 4): Draft, Research, and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Hook, ILA, Local 1258 Newsletter (photocopies), Aug 1934-Apr 1935 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Huberman, Leo: The NMU: What It Is, What It Does(pamphlet), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Hudson, Roy B.: Marine Workers Industrial Union Identification and Membership Book, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Industrial Union of Maritime and Shipbuilding Workers: Contract, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - International Longshore and Warehouse Union Attitude toward the Open Shop (Lundberg) Clause, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - International Organization of Masters, Mates, and Pilots Strike, Elizabethport, NJ: Flyer, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - International Seamen’s Union (ISU): Mass Protest Meeting (flyer), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - ISU: Membership Meeting on Board the SS California(photocopies), Feb 1936 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - ISU Strike: Appeal Addressed to "Colored Seamen," Flyer (photocopy), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - ISU Strike: Bulletins (photocopies), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - ISU Strike: Correspondence, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - ISU Strike: Minutes of Various Bodies, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - ISU Strike: Open Letters by W. B. Follett, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - ISU Strike: Rank and File Seamen Strike (Gulf Coast) Minutes, Flyers, Newsletters, Clippings (all photocopies), 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Jones, Rose (Secretary of the South Street Strike Hall): Oral History Transcript, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Kaufman, Sidney: Shipping Papers (photocopies), 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Keith, Charles: Fund Letter and "Charles Keith, A Seaman," Obituary by Bernard Nossiter, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Kempton, Murray: Correspondence with Morris Weiner re: NMU, 1949-1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Kempton, Murray: NMU Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Kramer, Jacob A.: "How Racism Was Used to Stymie Union Organizing of Great Lake Seamen" (typescript), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Labor Research Association: "Leaders in Labor’s Fight for Economic Security through a Peacetime Economy," Benefit Honoring Harry Bridges, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lynch, Barney: Correspondence to Greta Lynch (photocopies), 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lynch, Barney: Memorial Letter by Greta Lynch, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lynch, Barney: Obituary Letter by Johnny Gladstone, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lynch, Greta (Kornfeld): Biographical and General, 1943-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Lynch, Greta: NMU Women’s Auxiliary and Strike Cards, 1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lynch, Philip: Seamen’s Bank Book, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mandell, Sam: Oral History Transcript, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Margolin, Julius (Julie): Correspondence with U. S. Government and 1943 Margolin Clipping, 1943, 1966, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Marine Cooks’ and Stewards’ Association: Correspondence re: Members in the Spanish Civil War, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Marine Workers Historical Association (MWHA): By-Laws, Draft, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - MWHA: "First National Gathering," Conference, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - MWHA: Letter to Membership (incomplete), 1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - MWHA: Membership and Contact List, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - MWHA: Minutes, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - MWHA: Norval D. Welch and Johnny Gladstone Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - MWHA: Walking Tour Interview, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Marine Workers Industrial Union: The Bull Line Fighter, Vol. 1-1, No. 2 (photocopy), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Maritime Federation of the Gulf Coast: Organizing (Houston Longshoremen), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific, Educational Committee: The Yanks Are Not Coming(pamphlet), 1939 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Marx, Kathryn: Maritime Union History 1850s-1901(essay), undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - McCarthy, Bill: Art Shields Article on, undated, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - McKenzie, Howard (NMU): Memorial Service Announcement, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Merrell, James (Blackie): Memorial Tributes by Paul J. Jarvis and Morris Weiner, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Mers, Gil: Memoir (incomplete), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Morrissey, Jim: Clippings, 1979, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Myers, Frederick (Blackie): Certificates of Discharge and Service, 1934-1950 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Myers, Blackie: Financial Records, 1935-1948 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Myers, Blackie: Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Myers, Blackie: Obituary, The Dispatcher(photocopy), 1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Myers, Blackie: Personal Papers and Identification Cards, 1932-1951 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Nelles, Dieter: "I Prefer to March with the Army That’s Winning," Translated with Transcribed Remarks on Richard Krebs by Jan Valtin, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - New Bedford Strike of 1928: Clippings, Standard Times, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - NMU: "At Your Service," Personal Service Department Flyer, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - NMU: Bookstore Catalogue "Take a Book to Bed-Too!", undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - NMU: Clippings from the Joseph Padilla Collection, 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - NMU: CIO Certificate of Affiliation (photocopy), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - NMU: Committee for Democratic Unionism Bulletin, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - NMU: Companies under Agreement with NMU, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - NMU: Engine Division Membership Book (Alex Karpowski), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - NMU: Expulsions, Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - NMU: Expulsions, Drummond v. Curran, Aurelio Decision, etc., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - NMU: Founding, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - NMU: General, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - NMU: "High Wages for Merchant Seamen?...Read the Truth," Flyer, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - NMU: "Hitler’s Little Helper," Flyer in Spanish, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - NMU: Independent Caucus Anti-Expulsion Newsletters (Spanish and English), 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - NMU: National Convention Report, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - NMU: "New Revolt in the NMU," by Dorothy Day ( New Republic), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - NMU: Organizing West Coast Cooks and Stewards, Summary Reports, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - NMU: Port of New York Mobilization, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - NMU: Rank and File Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, "A Stone around the Seamen’s Neck," Draft of Open Letter, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, Anti-Curran Open Letters and Pamphlets, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, Bigotry in the Union, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, "Has Our Constitution Been Stoned?" (typescript), undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, New York Book Selling Scandal, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, Organizing New York Office Workers, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, Pension and Welfare Plan, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, Union Elections, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, Union Elections Membership Committee Ticket and Spanish Language Principles, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - NMU: Rank and File Dissent, U.S. Public Health Service Hospital Committee, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - NMU: Scrapbook (clippings), 1950-1979 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - NMU: "Songs for Seamen," Pamphlet, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - NMU: Staff Officers Association, Open Letter, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - NMU: Stewards Department Meeting on SS Exochorda, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - NMU: United Rank and File Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (U. S. Southern District Court) (pp. 1-67), Apr 20, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 68-unnumbered), Apr 20, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts, May 1, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts, Jul 20, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 1-50), Aug 10, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 51-144), Aug 10, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 145-209), Sep 14, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp.210-282), Sep 14, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 1-76), Sep 19, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 77-157), Sep 19, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 158-263), Sep 20, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 264-343), Sep 20, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 344-385), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 386-440), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 441-486), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 487-534), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 535-600), Sep 22, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 601-678), Sep 22, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 679-758), Sep 25, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 759-854b), Sep 25, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 854-928), Sep 26, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 929-1008), Sep 26, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 1009-1080), Sep 27, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts (pp. 1081-1176), Sep 27, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts, Oct 27, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - NMU: Wirtz, W. Willard v. NMU Transcripts, Nov 29, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - National Union of Marine Cooks and Stewards: President Hugh Bryson and Secretary-Treasurer Eddie Tangen Memos, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Nickerson, William, et al.: Complaints about Captain Harris Signed by Union Members aboard Unidentified Ship (missing first page), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Pacific District Stewards News", Jan 19, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Padilla, Joseph: Rank and File Dissent Materials, 1956-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Palazzi, Esther: Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pendulick, Nicholas: Shipping Papers, 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Petersen, T. H.: Soup Kitchen Meal Ticket (Maritime Federation of the Pacific Strike) and King Ramsey Defense Fund Receipt, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Postcards of Ships (unsent), 1973, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Postek, Stanley (Ladislaus F. Szeliga): Arrests, 1934-1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Postek, Stanley: Clippings (re: Boxing), 1937-1945 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Postek, Stanley: Delegate Papers (NMU/CIO), 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Postek, Stanley: Expulsion of Postek and J. L. Jackson, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Postek, Stanley: Journal aboard the SS Oneida, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Postek, Stanley: Membership Books, 1939-1967 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Postek, Stanley: Membership Standing, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Postek, Stanley: "My First Trip" Memoir (typescript), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Postek, Stanley: Security Appeal Hearing, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Postek, Stanley: Shipping Papers, 1936-1943 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Postek, Stanley: Strikes, 1937-1945 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Program for One National Union for Maritime Workers, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Ramos, David: "The Way it Was," NMU Pilot(Clipping), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reed, Clarence: "One Three or More" by "A. Novice" (typescript), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)